seorankmonitor.com 2019-05-08

# Privacy Policy - SEO Rank Monitor

_Effective on- 25-May-2018_

### 1\. Introduction

1.1 We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of our website visitors and service users.

1.2 This policy applies where we are acting as a data controller with respect to the personal data of our website visitors and service users; in other words, where we determine the purposes and means of the processing of that personal data.

1.3 We use cookies on our website. Insofar as those cookies are not strictly necessary for the provision of our website and services, we will ask you to consent to our use of cookies when you first visit our website.

1.4 Our website incorporates privacy controls which affect how we will process your personal data. By using the privacy controls, you can specify whether you would like to receive direct marketing communications and limit the publication of your information. To modify or delete the personal information you’ve provided to us and your settings, please log in and update your profile. You may also delete your account from your account settings page.

1.5 In this policy, “we”, “us” and “our” refer to **SEO Rank Monitor**. For more information about us, see **Section 10**.

### 2\. How we use your personal data

2.1 In this Section 2 we have set out:

(a) the general categories of personal data that we may process;

(b) the purposes for which we may process personal data; and

(d) the legal bases of the processing.

2.2 We may process data about your use of our website and services (“ **usage data** “). The usage data may include your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths, as well as information about the timing, frequency and pattern of your service use. The source of the usage data is our analytics tracking system. This usage data may be processed for the purposes of analysing the use of the website and services. The legal basis for this processing is consent OR our legitimate interests, namely monitoring and improving our website and services

2.3 We may process your account data (“ **account data** “). The account data may include your name and email address. The source of the account data is only you. The account data may be processed for the purposes of operating our website, providing our services, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you. The legal basis for this processing is consent OR our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business

2.4 We may process your personal data that are provided in the course of the use of our All services (“ **service data** “). The service data may include **SEO Services, purchasing, and other all services by SEO Rank Monitor**. The source of the service data is you. The service data may be processed for the purposes of operating our website, providing our services, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you. The legal basis for this processing is consent OR our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business

2.5 We may process information relating to transactions, including purchases of books and services, that you enter into with us and/or through our website (“ **transaction data** “). The transaction data may include your contact details, and the transaction ID only. The transaction data may be processed for the purpose of supplying the purchased goods and services and keeping proper records of those transactions.  
If you choose to pay for anything online at **https://members.seorankmonitor.com/subscription** using a Credit or Debit Card, your card details are not stored by us and cannot be used by our staff.

Your credit card details are encrypted and securely stored by **Braintree (PayPal)**.

A copy of Privacy policy you can found here <https://www.braintreepayments.com/en-pl/legal/braintree-privacy-policy>

2.6 We may process information that you provide to us for the purpose of subscribing to our email notifications and/or newsletters (“ **notification data** “). The notification data may be processed for the purposes of sending you the relevant notifications and/or newsletters. The legal basis for this processing is consent OR the performance of a contract between you and us.

2.7 Children’s Privacy. The Sites and Service are not structured to attract children under the age of 16, and we do not intend to collect Personal Data from anyone we know to be under 16. If we learn that we have collected Personal Data from anyone under 16 years, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any such information, please contact us at info@seorankmonitor.com.

2.8 We may process any of your personal data identified in this policy where necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the protection and assertion of our legal rights, your legal rights and the legal rights of others.

### 3\. Sharing your personal data to others

SEO Rank Monitor is an online tool people & companies use to monitor website’s search engine presence. When you create account SEO Rank Monitor provides several SEO Services along with payment through Braintree (PayPal). SEO Rank Monitor do not share user info to any third party for Ads, Newsletter and promotions.

### 4\. Retaining and deleting personal data

4.1 This Section 4 sets out our data retention policies and procedure, which are designed to help ensure that we comply with our legal obligations in relation to the retention and deletion of personal data.

4.2 Personal data that we process for any purpose or purposes shall not be kept for longer than is necessary for that purpose or those purposes.

4.3 We will retain your personal data as follows:

SEO Rank Monitor only keep personal details as long as it is necessary for the purpose for which it was collected. If you have provided us with your personal details, such as full name and address and requested a quotation from us or placed an order, we will keep your details on our database. We will remove your details at any time you request this of us, otherwise you should assume that the data will be kept on our systems indefinitely.

### 5\. Amendments

5.1 We may update this policy from time to time by publishing a new version on our website.

5.2 You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes to this policy.

5.3 We may notify you of changes OR significant changes to this policy by email or through the private messaging system on our website.

### 6\. Your rights

6.1 In this Section 6, we have summarized the rights that you have under data protection law. Some of the rights are complex, and not all of the details have been included in our summaries. Accordingly, you should read the relevant laws and guidance from the regulatory authorities for a full explanation of these rights.

6.2 Your principal rights under data protection law are:

(a) the right to access;

(b) the right to rectification;

(c) the right to erasure;

(d) the right to restrict processing;

(e) the right to object to processing;

(f) the right to data portability;

(g) the right to complain to a supervisory authority; and

(h) the right to withdraw consent.

6.3 You have the right to confirmation as to whether or not we process your personal data and, where we do, access to the personal data, together with certain additional information. That additional information includes details of the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal data concerned and the recipients of the personal data. Providing the rights and freedoms of others are not affected, we will supply to you a copy of your personal data.

6.4 You have the right to have any inaccurate personal data about you rectified and, taking into account the purposes of the processing, to have any incomplete personal data about you completed.

6.5 In some circumstances you have the right to the erasure of your personal data without undue delay. Those circumstances include: the personal data are no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed; you withdraw consent to consent-based processing; you object to the processing under certain rules of applicable data protection law; the processing is for direct marketing purposes; and the personal data have been unlawfully processed.

6.6 You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data on grounds relating to your particular situation, but only to the extent that the legal basis for the processing is that the processing is necessary for: the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of any official authority vested in us; or the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by us or by a third party. If you make such an objection, we will cease to process the personal information unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing is for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

6.7 You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes (including profiling for direct marketing purposes). If you make such an objection, we will cease to process your personal data for this purpose.

6.8 There are several ways you can stop direct marketing communications from us:

6.9.1 Click the ‘ **unsubscribe** ’ link in any email communication that we send you. We will then stop any further emails from that particular division. Communication email includes Marketing, Newsletter, Updates from SEO Rank Monitor.

6.9.2 If you have an account, log in to your **seorankmonitor.com** account and change your preferences. **SEO Rank Monitor** is not responsible for any accounts breaches from user end. We recommend you to make complex password while creating account and to change it timely.

Write to our Data Manager via info@seorankmonitor.com

Please note that you may continue to receive communications for a short period after changing your preferences while our systems are fully updated.

6.10 If you consider that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your habitual residence, your place of work or the place of the alleged infringement.

### 7\. About cookies

7.1 A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server.

7.2 Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.

7.3 Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

### 8\. Cookies that we use

8.1 We use cookies for the following purposes:

(a) we use session based cookies to retain session and for performance

(b) analytics – we use cookies to help us to analyse the use and performance of our website and services. We may also use analytics cookies to test new advertisements, pages, features or new functionality of the Service to see how our users react to them. (cookies used for this purpose are: google analytics)

### 9\. Managing cookies

9.1 Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You can however obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:

(a) <https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en> (Chrome);

(b) <https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences> (Firefox);

(c) <http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/> (Opera);

(d) <https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies> (Internet Explorer);

(e) <https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411> (Safari); and

(f) <https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy> (Edge).

9.2 Blocking all cookies will have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites.

9.3 If you block cookies, you will not be able to use all the features on our website.

### 10\. Our details

10.1 This website is owned and operated by **SEO Rank Monitor**

10.2 We are a registered corporation in Warsaw, Poland

### 11\. You can contact us:

(a) by direct email to – info@seorankmonitor.com

(b) using our website contact form at <http://www.seorankmonitor.com/contact/>

### 12\. Data protection officer

12.1 Our data protection officer’s contact details are:

Email Id- info@seorankmonitor.com

### Any questions?

We hope this Privacy Notice has been helpful in setting out the way we handle your personal data and your rights to control it. If you have any questions that haven’t been covered, please contact us by email – info@seorankmonitor.com

 **This policy was last updated on- 24-May-2018**
